<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>the playground</title><link href="http://play.mattlebrun.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://play.mattlebrun.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://play.mattlebrun.com/</id><updated>2013-08-09T13:46:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>the history of britannia</title><link href="http://play.mattlebrun.com/ultima-iv-game-journal-002.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-09T13:46:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:play.mattlebrun.com,2013-08-09:ultima-iv-game-journal-002.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I am faced with this unknown world I have decided to read and learn 
about it as much as I can before proceeding with my journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the most comfortable spot behind a large boulder nearby for I know 
not what danger could befall me in this unfriendly looking part of this 
land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also noticed that I am actually carrying with me packs of rations and 
a pencil and journal. I've decided to note down important and interesting 
stuff from the history book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;political history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This land called Britannia underwent an Age of Darkness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was when the land was terrorized by an evil wizard named Mondain 
who was later felled by an adventurer. However it was followed by 
restlessness for the people of Britannia can't seem to get over the terror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modain's terror soon lived anew through his apprentice Minax. Soon a new 
age of darkness befell the land. Her powers soon grew greater than her 
former master that it spread through time itself. Later heroes of legend 
emerged and killed her in her castle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For twenty years peace has roamed the land of Britannia. Then disturbing 
omens appeared and was later followed by an emergeance of a fiery island. 
This signified the third era of darkness. This story was accounted by 
Iolo, the bard. Lord British of Sosaria called through time and space for 
heroes. Four diverse individuals came to answer the call and soon the 
greatest battle of their time ensued. After ardous struggle, the heroes 
won and felled Exodus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the rubbles of Britannia, Lord British united the land under one rule 
and raised the quality of life in the land. Britannia is now in a new age 
of peace and progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the map that I have, I continued to read through the chapter 
that talked about the different places indicated. I was able to make out 
which place are being mentioned in the book as it appears in the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord British Castle - Situated in the center of the continent, overlooking 
Britanny Bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Town of Britain - Located near Lord British Castle. Bards thrive here. 
Perhaps I can find Iolo here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serpent's Spine - A great mountain range in the north of Lord British 
Castle. There's an out-of-the-way pass here during summer for faster 
travel. Beware of Cyclops and Ettins! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep Forest - Northwest of Serpent's Spine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;City of Yew - Located deep within the Deep Forest. Druids live here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empath Abbey - The Spiritual Center of Britannia located near the City of 
Yew. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High Steppes - Located in the east of the Deep Forest famous for their 
horses. This place seems to have a lot of Rogues and evil Wizards. There's 
also lake here known for mysterious disturbances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bloody Plains - Located just beyond the High Steppes. Named after the fact 
that it was a site for great battles during the dark ages. Rumor has it 
that in some phases of the moon ghosts appear and relive that battle once 
again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lost Hope Bay - Located north of the Bloody Plains. Tinkers live here. 
This town is also know for the Wayfarer's Inn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northeastern Tip of Brittania - Beware of poisonous marshes, large swarm 
of insects, and other vile beasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trinsic - Located in the southern edge of the continent. Here, I can find 
Paladins. The Tap has a bartender who is a great source of gossip. I'll 
remember to tip him well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cape of Heroes - Found in the claws of the southern edge of the continent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Order of Silver Serpent HQ - Found in an island south of Cape of Heroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valarian Isles - Slightly to the west of Cape of Heroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jhelom - An town within the Valarian Isles know for the best Inn and 
bravest Fighters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skara Brae - Home of the Rangers. Located in an island in the west of the 
continent. There's a Mystic Healer here who can cure all sorts of disease 
and you only pay what you can afford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verity Isle - Northeastern part of Britannia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lycaeum - Found within Verity Isle. It is the center of higher learning 
and astronomy in Britannia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moonglow - A city know for mages. Found in the south of Verity Isle. Here 
I can find herbs and regent to mix to prepare magical spells? Interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still several uncharted places here in Britannia but the ones 
that I have to be specially wary of is the &lt;em&gt;Fens of the Dead&lt;/em&gt;. It appears 
like all manner of evil roam this place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a place far off named &lt;em&gt;Magincia&lt;/em&gt; which the gods have 
destroyed because of the insufferable pride of the people who lived there. 
Magincia was once a rich and beautiful town but its now in complete ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;wait a minute...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magincia sounds familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I glanced over the rock from which I was sitting and looked at the ruins 
a few meters away. There's a sign in one of the pillars the read 
&lt;em&gt;"Magincia"&lt;/em&gt;. The books says this town is filled with ailing spirits of 
the inhabitants. No wonder this place feels unfriendly. I better stay away 
from that place for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book also mentioned to avoid the dungeons scattered all over the 
continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;fellowship&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be eight major professions in the whole of Britannia. All 
of them are based from one of the major towns mentioned in the geography 
except for one - the &lt;em&gt;Shepherd&lt;/em&gt;. Also all the other seven professions 
appear to have their own specialty and coolness factor except for the 
Shepherd, whom the book describes as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is uncertain whether Shepherds are skilled in any form of warfare or 
in the mystic arts. However, they are highly valued travelling 
companions for their humility and their knowledge of the ways of the 
land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great! Looks like I got the worst profession in this land after all. No 
magic, no fighting skills... This is going to be tough. But I'm also not 
afraid of anything. I'll get by somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also looks like I'll need to find companions along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;mercantile&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A variety of shops are found in each town. There are Inns, Pubs, Armories, 
Weaponries, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside Lord British Castle, lives Seer Hawkwind who can give advice about 
the path I have to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a persisting rumor that a Thieves Guild still exists 
somewhere in one of the uncharted islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Herb shop sells ingredients needed to perform spells. Some rare 
ingredients are not sold all the time if not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;transportation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah this is most important for a journeyman such as myself. There are 
several modes of transportation in Britannia: Feet, Horse, Ship. But the 
most interesting method though is via Moon Gates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The active gate is indicated by the phase of the moon Trammel, while the 
destination gate is indicated by the phase of the moon Felucca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that explains the moon illustrations all over the map as well as the 
two moons I see in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, of all the terrain types in Britannia the most dangerous one are the 
marshes because of its poisonous vapors. Come to think of it, there are 
marshes all over this place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lycaeum appears to have been working on a lighter than air device but 
the blueprints have been stolen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;weapons and armour of the realm&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the available weaponry and armours I can only wear cloth and either 
use a staff or a slingshot. I guess a bow is worth a try as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also rumours of magical weapons and armor but they'll become 
available when the weilder is ready. How?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;magical arts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret is a proper mix of the available ingredients. I think the other 
book can guide me here better. But I must find a companion who can wield 
magic first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most powerful ingredients: Nightshade and Mandrake root are not for 
sold anywhere. I wonder where I can find them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;bestiary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears that there's a number of creatures in this realm but they're 
either neutral or evil types. I guess its better to avoid the evil ones at 
all cost and avoid killing the neutral ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;the skills of combat&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can summarize the notes indicated in the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always be prepared before engaging the enemy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid killing neutral enemies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take advantage of terrain tactics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not cowardly to flee when necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;modern civilization and our universe&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter explained a lot the reason behind this whole incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks like in this new age of peace where the focus of human development 
is no longer about expanding territory and fighting a world terror, a 
question needs answering. What is the next step in human evolution? What 
should be our focus to keep the peace we are enjoying and demonstrate what 
we have learned from the wrongs of the past?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this question we must turn inward. Look within ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author went on with an interesting premise that one must journey and 
learn the ways of the world and discover the essence of good. A journey to 
become an &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt; of all the virtues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like the book mentions that this is the journey that I have to 
take and that this is my destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all seems unbelievable to me. Why me? I'm just a regular peaceful guy 
going on about my life. Though I've always been someone who tries to seek 
out my purpose outside of the mundane, this is just too much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really have to see Lord British and talk to him. Maybe he can send me 
back to my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Notes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whew that was a handful! But I think writing it all was quite worth it. It 
made me realize certain aspects of the game that I didn't quite understand 
when I was playing it back in 2001. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally understood how those damn Moon Gates work!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ultima-iv"></category></entry><entry><title>the quest begins</title><link href="http://play.mattlebrun.com/ultima-iv-game-journal-001.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-06T22:35:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:play.mattlebrun.com,2013-08-06:ultima-iv-game-journal-001.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a very challenging week for me and I just wanted to escape from 
it all. Life hasn't really been treating me well. The new job didn't quite 
turned out what I wanted to do after all, I had a fight with my 
girlfriend, my parents are having all sorts of domestic issues. Oh man!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good thing its the weekend and I can finally get some peace and quiet by 
the willow tree in the nearby hills. I really like hanging out here. It 
really relaxes my mind and I can be calm and still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;a strange happening&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was just about to fall a sleep when a some kind of portal appeared a few 
meters in front of me. There was a bright light and in an instant the 
portal disappeared. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then saw something glimmer and then there was a loud &lt;em&gt;"thud"&lt;/em&gt;. Walking 
towards the sound, I saw a cross with a circle on top of it. People call 
this an &lt;em&gt;"Ankh"&lt;/em&gt;. I heard the Egyptians thinks of it as a symbol of life. 
Right beside it are a couple of books wrapped in cloth which resembles a 
map with strange writings on it. One of the books is a history book and 
the other one is a strange looking book about magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, I am compelled to read the history book. So I browsed over it, 
but shortly decided to put it away for now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;beyond the hills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly I heard a mix of merry music and laughter behind a nearby hill. 
I was attracted to it. As I was approaching the source of the sound, I was 
welcomed with a sight of a carnival. I'm pretty sure there's no carnival 
here before. Its all very strange indeed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued walking towards the entrance. When the guard saw my Ankh he 
ushered me right in. I was then attracted to a strange music coming from a 
wagon. I walked straight for it, not minding the rest of the carnival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside, I was met by a Gypsy who's also wearing an Ankh. She mentioned 
something about they've been waiting for me. She then told me that its 
time to reveal my destiny. I feel very strange and creeped out right now 
but I'm somehow curious to know what is she talking about. So I decided to 
play along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;going spiral&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She brought out some cards and an abacus-like object minus the beads and 
begun asking me situational questions depending on the card the she 
picked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I answered them honestly and once the final question was answered, the 
Gypsy said that my path is set. Suddenly, I started feeling very dizzy. 
Everything around me suddenly turned spiral. Before I lost consciousness, 
I heard the Gypsy told me to seek out the King to find out what my mission 
is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;the journey begins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I regained my consciousness, I found myself lying on the ground with 
staff on my hand. The Ankh is around my neck and the map and books were 
right beside me. I'm also wearing a brownish robe and tunic, just like the 
shepherds I see in pictures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land around me is very strange and seems dangerous. Suddenly I 
remembered the events that transpired before I got here. I'm supposed to 
find the King of this land. I remembered his name is Lord British. But how 
do I get there and where am I exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if my problems aren't big enough, now I'm stuck in some strange land 
with no clue on what's happening. I'm both terrified and strangely excited 
at the same time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrified of what perils are in stored for me here yet excited by the 
smell of adventure and new discoveries. I've always been the curious, 
adventurous type after all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I better finish reading the history book to get some clues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Notes&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, I actually got a Shepherd class character. I 
haven't played this class before and I'm quite excited to play him out. Oh 
and I named him &lt;code&gt;Eli&lt;/code&gt;. It just seems like I've been quite fond of using 
that name for my characters lately. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, notice that I've decided to write the story in first-person POV for 
better immersion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Ultima IV is one of those games where you really have to play out 
the role to get the most out of the game. Its not just about 
hack-and-slashing your way through the game or making the best character 
build or unlocking the next achievement or highscore. Its a genuine 
experience where the game doesn't hold your hand and leaves you in a 
massive world waiting for you to experience and discover its secrets and 
grandeur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, be forewarned: There will be typos and grammatical errors!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ultima-iv"></category></entry><entry><title>a gaming blog</title><link href="http://play.mattlebrun.com/a-gaming-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-06T18:25:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:play.mattlebrun.com,2013-08-06:a-gaming-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The games of old are nothing like the games of this age."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was my prevailing thought after a long chat with Ron and Ray about 
how different are the games of this generation compared to the games of 
the 80's and the 90's. We reminisced about how nostalgic and elaborate 
are the games of that time. They just have a longer lasting effect and 
develops a deep connection to the gamer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I was starting out with getting back at the games that I 
used to play at that time and I thought why not write about the 
adventures of the characters that I play since I'm mostly playing RPGs. 
I can also write about the kinds of games that I play and even write a 
review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why am I doing this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly for the heck of it and it'll be a good exercise for my creative 
and imaginative side. It might even contribute to one of my long-term 
goals of creating my own graphic novel / game.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="thoughts"></category></entry></feed>