<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>the playground</title><link href="http://play.mattlebrun.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://play.mattlebrun.com/feeds/game-journal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://play.mattlebrun.com/</id><updated>2013-08-06T22:35:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>the quest begins</title><link href="http://play.mattlebrun.com/ultima-iv-game-journal-001.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-06T22:35:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:play.mattlebrun.com,2013-08-06:ultima-iv-game-journal-001.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a very challenging week for me and I just wanted to escape from 
it all. Life hasn't really been treating me well. The new job didn't quite 
turned out what I wanted to do after all, I had a fight with my 
girlfriend, my parents are having all sorts of domestic issues. Oh man!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good thing its the weekend and I can finally get some peace and quiet by 
the willow tree in the nearby hills. I really like hanging out here. It 
really relaxes my mind and I can be calm and still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;a strange happening&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was just about to fall a sleep when a some kind of portal appeared a few 
meters in front of me. There was a bright light and in an instant the 
portal disappeared. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then saw something glimmer and then there was a loud &lt;em&gt;"thud"&lt;/em&gt;. Walking 
towards the sound, I saw a cross with a circle on top of it. People call 
this an &lt;em&gt;"Ankh"&lt;/em&gt;. I heard the Egyptians thinks of it as a symbol of life. 
Right beside it are a couple of books wrapped in cloth which resembles a 
map with strange writings on it. One of the books is a history book and 
the other one is a strange looking book about magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, I am compelled to read the history book. So I browsed over it, 
but shortly decided to put it away for now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;beyond the hills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly I heard a mix of merry music and laughter behind a nearby hill. 
I was attracted to it. As I was approaching the source of the sound, I was 
welcomed with a sight of a carnival. I'm pretty sure there's no carnival 
here before. Its all very strange indeed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued walking towards the entrance. When the guard saw my Ankh he 
ushered me right in. I was then attracted to a strange music coming from a 
wagon. I walked straight for it, not minding the rest of the carnival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside, I was met by a Gypsy who's also wearing an Ankh. She mentioned 
something about they've been waiting for me. She then told me that its 
time to reveal my destiny. I feel very strange and creeped out right now 
but I'm somehow curious to know what is she talking about. So I decided to 
play along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;going spiral&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She brought out some cards and an abacus-like object minus the beads and 
begun asking me situational questions depending on the card the she 
picked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I answered them honestly and once the final question was answered, the 
Gypsy said that my path is set. Suddenly, I started feeling very dizzy. 
Everything around me suddenly turned spiral. Before I lost consciousness, 
I heard the Gypsy told me to seek out the King to find out what my mission 
is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;the journey begins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I regained my consciousness, I found myself lying on the ground with 
staff on my hand. The Ankh is around my neck and the map and books were 
right beside me. I'm also wearing a brownish robe and tunic, just like the 
shepherds I see in pictures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land around me is very strange and seems dangerous. Suddenly I 
remembered the events that transpired before I got here. I'm supposed to 
find the King of this land. I remembered his name is Lord British. But how 
do I get there and where am I exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if my problems aren't big enough, now I'm stuck in some strange land 
with no clue on what's happening. I'm both terrified and strangely excited 
at the same time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrified of what perils are in stored for me here yet excited by the 
smell of adventure and new discoveries. I've always been the curious, 
adventurous type after all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I better finish reading the history book to get some clues.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ultima-iv"></category></entry></feed>